# Jesse Emamalie Web Developer

JesseETI

### **Profile**

A highly passionate web developer with domain experience in React.js, TypeScript, and JavaScript. I work remotely with teams located across the Caribbean and Latin America in the Agile environment to develop, test and deploy web applications.

# **Skills**

# React-Typescript & JavaScript

React.js, Typescript-react, Redux, Context API, React Hook Form, React-Query

### Styling

Material-UI, Chakra UI, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, CSS, Storybook UI

### Deployment

Microsoft Azure DevOps, Heroku, Netlify, Google **Firebase** 

# UI / UX

**Figma** 

### Java

**Spring Boot** 

#### **Version Control**

Git

#### **Testing**

Test-Driven Development, Mock API Testing

### **Agile Methodology**

SCRUM, Jira, Confluence

## **Professional Experience**

## **Frontend Developer,** CIBC FirstCaribbean Bank

03/2022 – present | Remote, Contract

- Developed a CRM front end using React, TypeScript, and Chakra UI. Proper emphasis is made on following linting rules, documentation, accessibility, and testing.
- Worked alongside the product owner and scrum master by routinely leading backlog refinements, weekly demos, sprint reviews, and conceptualization meetings.
- Worked alongside the technical lead by routinely performing Backend, QA, and UI Design reviews and offering feedback on code and screen designs.

# Freelance Web Developer, ETI Designs

06/2021 – present | Remote

- Developed modern portfolio and eCommerce websites for small businesses, achieving 95% customer satisfaction and new sales revenue.
- Sharpened my expertise in full-stack design, development, and DevOps by creating several SaaS applications, found on my GitHub profile □.

# Full Stack Web Developer, UWI Health Services Unit Pharmacy

01/2021 - 05/2021 | Remote

- Built an MVP eCommerce platform and CRM with a 36% faster loading time than the previous website.
- Converted UX/UI wireframe designs to documented web components using Nuxt.js and TailwindCSS.
- Worked with an agile team of 5 members, serving as Scrum Master for 2 sprints.

### **Education**

BSc. Computer Science, University of the West Indies First Class Honours, Dean's Honor Roll 2021

09/2018 - 09/2021